You can 't just say you don 't know . That 's what you said on the phone .
When will you know ?
I ... don 't know .
Do you want me to spend the night somewhere else ?
In a hotel or something ?
Do you want us to meet later on ? We can talk more calmly . Do you ...
Do you need more time ?
What ... ? What do you need ?
What has happened ?
Bob knows that you are coming back today .
Well , I can ...
I can pick him up after school and take him ...
to the zoo or something .
( BOB IMITATES SIREN )
Come and admire him .
BOB : Nee-na , nee-na , nee-na .
Nee-na , nee-na .
ANNA : Maybe all couples go through this .
Yeah .
One mustn 't be afraid .
No .
One must speak honestly .
Is that difficult ?
Is it difficult ?
I haven 't been much help but I 've finished that job now - it 's over .
Maybe I was asking for too much .
I was the one who had the right to ask .
I know .
No , you don 't .
Who was I doing it for , after all ?
Were you unfaithful to me ?
The truth is not really .
Were you ?
No .
There 's always someone else when these things happen .
Not in this case .
All right , well ...
What 's happening to us is just ...
It 's just natural . Feelings ...
change .
But without you I wouldn 't feel anything at all .
What do you feel now ?
Are you really interested ?
No .
There you are , you see . It 's the same with me .
I don 't even want you now .
- What time did you meet him ? - 8.30 .
- Where ? - In the park .
- Was he willing ? - Yes , verbally .
Did you sense or detect weariness in him ?
No . A correct appraisal of the realities .
- Is it making him bitter ? - No . Greedy .
But you felt his power ?
You mean did I feel fear ?
No because that would have prevented me answering all your questions .
- How many vials did he take with him ? - Two .
What procedure have you devised for contacting him again ?
It 's all in my report .
I suggest it 's more economical to fill in my successor .
We don 't feel there is a need for a successor .
I 've completed my job .
Brilliantly . That 's why we want to rehire you .
It 's out of the question .
And what would be the reason for your refusal ?
Family .
- Couldn 't we be of some help there ? - No .
Wouldn 't it be advisable for you to reconsider ?
I 'm unable to do that .
Would you be unable for a long time ?
I hope not .
Aren 't you allowing feelings to prevent you from answering your own questions ?
Exactly why I advise you to hire my successor .
Good .
Any questions ?
No .
Does our subject still wear pink socks ?
Anna ?
( PHONE RINGS )
It 's me .
It 's Anna ?
I am downtown .
Why downtown ? I 've been waiting all day .
I need some time to think .
What do you mean " to think " ? Think about what ?
To think about me .
Wh ... Wh ... Where are you ?
- When will you ... ? - ( PHONE CUTS OFF )
( RING TONE )
- Hello ? - Margie , this is Mark .
Now , I know there 's no sympathy between us and it 's ...
hard for me to ask you for help but ...
you 're her only friend . Now , just tell me the truth .
She has somebody ?
She wished you 'd say or do something . Something to reinstall you .
You know , a magic wave of the wand .
You arrived sooner than expected , Mark .
Yes , sure , this is all my fault . Now , how long has this been going on ?
Quite long .
Who is he ?
Oh , Mark ! I don 't ...
Your wife keeps her own secrets .
Margie ...
I don 't have a magic wand . I don 't intend to hang on .
But make her talk to me . It 'll be the way that she wants .
But this is not
proper .
- Please . - ( PHONE CUT OFF )
( CONTINUOUS TONE )
( PHONE RINGS )
Yes ?
We 're over , Mark .
You have someone .
Yes .
- For a long time ? - Does it matter ?
Do you
sleep with him ?
Yes .
- Do you like it ? - Yes .
More than with me ?
Yes .
I see .
How do you intend to live now ?
- We have to discuss it . - Now .
As you want .
Half an hour at the Cafe Einstein .
I 'm too far for half an hour .
Are you calling from there ?
Yes .
Is he listening ?
No .
But he is there .
Yes .
Would 800 a month for Bob be enough ?
I suppose .
Will you move in with him or keep the apartment ?
I 'll keep it if you allow me to .
I 've decided not to see Bob .
- At all ? - At all .
How can you say that ?
He 's going to be fucked up enough as it is .
I don 't want to fuck him up even more by playing Sunday Daddy .
- What were you to him anyway ? - Precisely .
But ...
He knows you . He 's yours . He needs ...
A real father full time ?
Well , I thought I could be , coming home from the war , so to speak .
You say it 's better with him than with me .
I get bored of it .
Tell me .
I think what you want to do to Bob is ...
Inhuman ? So what you 're doing must be human .
- How long is it going to last ? - I don 't know .
One week ? Two weeks ?
And how do you dispose of ideas like honesty and loyalty ?
If I could only believe that it happened cleanly at first sight .
OK , if it makes things easier ,
I was in his bed the first night I met him , if you have to know .
What do you expect of me ? Look what you 're doing .
No-one is good or bad
but if you want , I am the bad one
and if I knew he existed in this world , I would have never had Bob with you .
Get out !
Get out ! Get out !
( SCREAMING )
( RINGING TONE )
( WOMAN SPEAKS FAINTLY )
- Erm ... - Hallo ?
Mm ...
Hallo ? Hallo ?
Ma , ma , ma .
( THUNDER AND RAIN )
( PANTING )
How ... How long have I ... ?
How long have I been here ?
Three weeks , sir .
What happened ? It 's Daddy .
Mummy said she would be right back but she never came .
Then Margie called and told me to be brave
because she had broke her leg and she had to have the cast put on .
You 've been alone for a long time ?
Look , I got a new boat .
Did you get it from Mummy ?
No . From Uncle Heinrich .
Long ago ?
Yes .
Yesterday ?
No . Before you were coming back from far away .
OK , little piggy .
Come on , let 's get out of this mess .
How did you make such a mess ?
( KEY IN LOCK )
This is not always like this , Mark . Usually I 'm on time .
I 'm not interested .
I came to tell you that I can 't live without you
and I 'm ready to understand whatever there is
but it doesn 't look like it makes much sense .
- You can 't take Bob away from me . - I 'm not trying .
You can continue to visit whenever you want , but I 'm taking over here .
Anna , is there anything I can do ?
- You could just ... - Yes ?
- I must ... - Yes ?
I must ...
You must restore order . You must leave him .
You will call him . You will say it is over .
Now , I don 't care if you tell him you love him
but he 's not your family - your family is here .
You must call him now .
- But I can 't on the phone . - I don 't trust you .
- I have to tell him face to face . - I don 't trust you .
On the phone .
Oh Jesus !
Jesus ! Jesus ! Jesus !
Jesus !
If you want to stay , make that call .
It 's still quite warm . I don 't think you 'll need a winter coat or sweater .
I can 't stand to see you like this .
It could be the way you want . Just don 't cry any more .
I am very sleepy .
( PHONE RINGS )
Anna is with me and she 'll stay with me .
He phoned me . He said she won 't be coming back .
I have to talk to her right now . Please give me that number .
542-6261 .
Where is it ?
I don 't know , Mark .
542-6261 .
( PUNCHES NUMBERS )
( RINGING TONE )
- Hello ? - Yes ?
I want to speak to Heinrich .
My son is not in town . Who is calling ?
Anna 's husband .
Anna 's not here . I haven 't seen her for weeks .
I miss her so much .
Hallo ? Hallo ?
- Hallo ? - ( SLAMS PHONE DOWN )
( WHISPERS ) 542-6261
What happened ?
Wee-wee .
Shall I take you ?
Where 's Mummy ?
She went to see Margie .
Are you going too ?
I 'm staying with you .
Hello , I 'm Bob 's father . I 'll be bringing him to school from now on .
I 'm glad . You 're the father who went far away and met the polar bears .
Hello .
What is this ? A joke ?
What are you talking about ?
- I mean your wig . - What ?
I 'm so sorry . It 's impossible .
Have you ever seen my wife ?
Naturally . Every day of the school year .
You 're Heinrich ?
Yes .
I 've come for Anna .
Anna 's not here .
You want me to break down the bloody door ?
You don 't have to . It 's open .
We don 't have to be brutal to each other or even impolite .
Our situation is like a mountain lake we are trying to swim in ,
starting from different shores .
I am not astonished you are here .
I was thinking about you just before you came
so now that you 're here , let 's be open to each other .
You can hate me as much as you like .
But it 's you who wants to know things from me .
So please make it possible .
I am suffering as much as you are .
The fact that Anna did not inform you was harmful to everyone
but I always accept Anna 's ways ,
as I think no-one has a right to impose his will on anyone .
So that 's how you 've changed her so much .
Possibly , but is it changing her or making her open to herself ?
So open she 's inarticulate at night and you have to speak for her ?
What are you talking about ?
We spoke on the phone last night , you and I , didn 't we ?
Stop it . I just arrived from Hamburg . You weren 't listening to me .
I was just trying to make her comprehend that I love her .
I left the day you arrived to give her the chance to decide for herself .
I allowed you your chance .
Bullshit !
I 'm not obliged to listen to you speak in that way . It 's offensive .
How long have you been fucking me over ?
A year .
All my visits home , all that time .
Yes .
And this is what you mean by accepting Anna 's ways ?
Precisely .
The key being the infinitive .
To accept .
I have been honest with you .
Would you permit me to enquire on a specific point ?
On your last visit home , were you content with your wife ?
I mean sexually .
Why ?
Because in that period we reached a state of perfect harmony .
Er ...
My mother .
- Is she here all the time ? - Yes .
- Even when you 're fucking Anna ? - Of course .
Agh !
Why ?
( GROANS )
( GROANS AGAIN )
BOB : ... eating green bananas .
Where d 'you think he put the skins ? Down his new pyjamas !
( ANNA LAUGHS )
Yes . Yes !
Baa baa black sheep , have you any wool ?
Yes sir , yes sir , three bags full .
One for ... the master , one for the dame
and one for the little boy that lives down the lane .
- Can I go out into the back yard ? - Yes , you may .
But you take your sandwich with you .
Where were you ?
I wrote you . I was at Margie 's .
That 's not true . I spoke to her .
I was with him .
That 's not true either . I saw him . I may ... stink from him .
- But he 's not lying . - I was ...
- I was with friends . - Who ?
- New friends . - I 'll check .
Yes , check , check , check , check , check !
Why did you leave last night ?
To be alone !
But you said you went to friends .
Why are you nagging me ? Can 't you just leave me in peace ?
I could have perfect peace if you never came back .
It 's Bob ! I have Bob ! He is my son too .
Don 't try to tell me you care about him all that much .
He didn 't stop you from breaking us up .
If you really thought about him , you 'd give a thought to us , for Christ 's sake .
I do ! I do !
No you don 't . You think about buying him a pair of shoes ,
about making him a snack , about telling him a bedtime story
but if you really thought about him , you 'd think about us .
Right , right . Why are you always right ? But it 's difficult , don 't you understand ?
It 's difficult . I didn 't want it to happen but it happened and now ...
Don 't come any closer .
Anna , it 's me .
Don 't you understand ? You disgust me .
I can 't stand you touching me .
You make me ...
You know , love isn 't something you can just switch from channel to channel .
I have your letters . " My love , trust me , " you write
and all the time you were fucking your arse off .
- You want me to believe you 're a ... - A whore ! Yes !
A monster , a whore . I fuck around with everybody .
Whenever you turn around I fuck around with everybody on every corner .
You will let me go .
Please don 't make me force you .
You can 't stop me .
I 'll open the window and jump .
You need him that much ?
Oh yes ! Oh yes !
Fuck your needs !
Do it again .
Agh !
( SHE SCREAMS )
( SHE GROANS )
You know what this is for ?
The lies .
Then you 'll have to add much more .
Bitch !
( DOOR SLAMS )
( FOOTSTEPS ECHO )
Bitch ! You bitch !
- What 's going to happen to us ? - It 's up to you .
- Then stop coming . - I have to go .
I 'll follow you .
Don 't even try .
( CHILDREN SHOUTING )
Oh , it 's Aunt Margit , the angel of the extinct hearth , limping to the rescue .
And nothing can stop me .
Oh ! I know you can 't wait to run off and make a fool of yourself
and I 'm here to help you .
I 'll look after Bob . Give me your sweater .
Ah !
I loathe you , Marge .
You 're still full of belief , Mark .
I love seeing you miserable .
It 's so reassuring .
Shit , Marge .
Yes , sir .
Mr Zimmerman will be with you in a minute .
The second door on the right .
Yes .
Sir .
How can we help you ? Please .
I , er ...
I would like you to follow my
wife for a few days .
Of course . Wives , wives , wives , wives .
Are there any reasons you would like to give us ?
You don 't have to answer but often it is enormously helpful in an investigation .
My wife doesn 't live with me any more
but she visits - or at least she has been visiting up to now - my son .
I see .
I have a photo of my wife here .
Are there any other leads ?
Mmm .
Family ?
Does your wife have a job ?
She quit about a year ago .
Friends ?
Her best friend is Mrs Margie Gluckmeister . She 's in the directory .
Margie visits our place occasionally to ...
to help out with Bob .
All right , sir . Now we must get down to practicalities .
Oh ! Look at this .
Tired boy .
Let 's get you in bed .
That 's it .
( DOGS BARKING OUTSIDE )
Oh , look at this .
Tired boy . Let 's get you in bed .
That 's it .
On with the covers .
( DOOR UNLOCKS )
( DOOR SLAMS )
Excuse me .
How long is this going to last ?
I 'm talking to you .
Excuse me !
You don 't have the right to behave this way .
What have I done that you hate me so much ?
- ( CARVING KNIFE BUZZES ) - Nothing .
- I deserve this ? - Get off it . No .
Get off it .
- Told you to stop coming home . - Get off , get off , get off !
This is disgusting .
Yes .
Look what we 've become .
Talk to me .
I don 't want you to be like this .
You know , when I 'm away from you I think of you as an animal ,
or a woman possessed
and then I see you again and all this disappears .
( MINCER BUZZES )
You must try and help me .
Tell me .
Maybe it will help .
Are you happy ?
Do you love him ? Does he love you ?
Do you want to live together ?
And have a family and ...
Am I in your way and Bob too ?
And there 's something else you must tell me .
Why are you afraid to tell me ?
Are you afraid of me ? Are you ... ?
Are you afraid I 'll get mad again and beat you ?
Are you afraid I won 't like you ?
Yes .
Anna , help me .
Help me !
( SHE SCREAMS )
Oh my God !
No ! No ! No !
Anna , there 's Bob . There 's Bob , remember .
Good Christ ! Remember .
( SCREAMING SLOWS )
It 'll be the way you want it .
Hold it .
You don 't have to say anything you don 't want to .
You 're my whole family .
I have to go now .
Would you wait for Bob ?
I can 't now .
Maybe we can both go and pick him up at school .
I can 't .
It doesn 't hurt .
No .
( CHURCH BELLS RINGING )
I gotten your wife 's address . It 's in Kreuzberg .
Sebastianstrasse 87 , 1st floor .
She seems to be alone .
Do you want me to check this now ?
Danke .
Sorry to bother you , miss . I 'm from the building manager 's office .
We had a complaint about some broken windows somewhere
and the glass falling down on the sidewalk .
- Is that what it is ? - I 'm afraid I have to check your windows .
- But I can assure you they 're all right . - How can you be so sure ?
I just ... I just saw you come in .
It 'll only take a moment .
But I don 't want you to be here .
I quite understand , miss , but it 's me or the police .
A lady got hurt on the sidewalk , a Turkish woman .
You might say she shouldn 't be here in the first place but she lodged a complaint .
So what can I do about it ?
Nothing .
Please .
Is it OK ?
Moment .
So ?
Excuse me , the bathroom ?
The bathroom doesn 't have a window .
Are you sure ?
Absolutely .
Some bathrooms have windows this side of the house .
Not in this one .
I 'm afraid I still have to check it before someone else gets ...
Would you care for a glass of wine ?
- Wine ? - Yes .
I 'm afraid I ...
Yes , wine !
- I 'm afraid you ... - Oh , come on . Don 't be so formal .
Miss , it doesn 't make any sense . I 've got k-k-kids .
I only came for the windows .
I 'm sorry , miss , but ...
I still have to have a look .
Oh ! It broke !
( SQUELCHING AND DRIPPING )
Was ist ... ?
( SHE SCREAMS )
( SHE SCREAMS AGAIN )
How long ?
Ah ... Ages and ages .
- Much longer than I could . - ( DOOR BUZZER )
BOB : Nee-na , nee-na , nee-na .
Hello , I 'm sorry to bother you so late . May I see your wife ?
No . She went out .
BOB : Nee-na , nee-na , nee-na .
That 's not entirely true . She ...
She doesn 't live with us any longer .
Oh .
It 's about Bob .
Ah ! Bob !
Bob is fine .
He 's just beaten the world record in tub diving .
Oh ! ( SHE LAUGHS )
- Hello , Bob . - Come on . Cut it out , Bob .
( DOOR BUZZER )
( BUZZING CONTINUES )
Look , um ...
- Would you be so kind ? - ( BUZZER CONTINUES )
He 's actually been in the bath for about an hour .
Yes , of course .
I 've called many times .
I wanted to discuss with you the redistribution of our parts
in this fundamentally vulgar structure , the triangle .
In other words , where is she ?
I 've been giving a great deal of thought to the illogical aspects
of your anger and your defence .
Is Anna with you ?
And if ?
I would only ask to have a talk with her .
What if I said no ?
I 'm sorry I used violence with you .
Now I 'd only apply my psychic process to make her come to me .
Oh , I 'm so sorry , she 's not here .
Did I tell you I had a wife and a daughter ?
No !
They live in Cincinnati .
What does that do for you ?
They will always remain my first family .
Anna could be the second and you and Bob in some sense .
Do you have a dog ?
Would that I had .
You misuse me .
It 's stiff and blocked men like you that lead us to the concentration camp .
Who are the crusaders of every blind principle , so-called ideology
humanity invents to strangle me ?
Why don 't you like me ?
Why don 't you draw in the plentitude of my love
and pull it all over your life like a veil ?
OK , I like you .
And I can tell you where Anna lives .
Lives ?
Only ... I don 't know the guy 's name .
It 's impossible . It doesn 't make sense .
Why not ?
Because you think you 've given her the supreme pleasure ?
You with your yin-yang balls dangling from your zen brain .
OK , maybe it does boil down to a sexual contest , in which case ...
I 'm sure you win hands down .
- But is that all ? - BOB : Nee-na , nee-na .
Nee-na , nee-na , nee-na .
( BOB CONTINUES )
I used to be afraid of you .
But I don 't think I am any more .
There 's nothing to fear except God .
Whatever that means to you .
For me God is a disease .
That 's why through the disease we can reach God .
" Tracking something , " said Winnie-the-Pooh very mysteriously .
" Tracking what ? " said Piglet , coming closer .
" That 's just what I ask myself . I ask myself , What ? "
" What do you think you 'll answer ? "
He wants to say good night to you .
Thank you .
You smell clean .
Do you like Helen ?
I think so .
Are you not sure ?
Well , I don 't know her yet .
Do you like her ?
Yes , and who don 't you like ?
Well , I don 't like Heinrich
and I don 't like that sailboat .
Why ? He 's funny .
I don 't like ...
I don 't like Mummy to like him more than us .
Who 's prettier ? Mummy or Helen ?
Who do you think is prettier ?
You tell me .
Our Mummy .
Good night , son .
Thank you .
Do you have anyone to help you with him ?
Oh it 's ... It 's not a problem . I ...
I have plenty of time .
Bob won 't say anything to me . He keeps his words for himself .
He knows everything , senses everything . Children are amazing .
Yeah .
After lunch we have an hour 's rest .
Bob very often goes to sleep .
When he does he cries or shouts .
Does he do it at home ?
No .
Oh .
He screams .
It is very difficult to calm him down .
When he wakes up he pretends that nothing happened .
What can I say ?
I 'm at war against women .
They ... have no foresight .
There 's nothing about them that is stable , there 's nothing to trust .
They 're dangerous .
There is nothing in common among women except menstruation .
Excuse me .
I come from a place where evil seems easier to pinpoint
because you can see it in the flesh .
It becomes people so you know exactly the danger of being deformed by it .
Which doesn 't mean I admire your world .
But I find pathetic these stories of women contaminating the universe .
I 'm ...
I 'm one of the contaminated .
Because you never feel free , do you ?
So sad that for you freedom seems to mean evil .
And what about lack of freedom ?
It 's extraordinary .
All right .
Together we can listen if Bob cries out .
You don 't have to make love to me .
I 'm not trying .
( BOB SCREAMING )
What happened ?
I want Mummy ! My Mummy !
- Mummy ! My Mummy ! Mummy ! Mummy ! - It 's OK . It 's all right .
- It 's OK . It 's all right . - Mummy ! Mummy ! Mummy !
- It 's all right . It 's all right . - Mummy ! Mummy ! Mummy !
( BOB WHIMPERS )
( WHISPERS ) It 's all right . It 's all right . It 's all right .
It 's all right . Sh !
I 'm sorry .
It wasn 't very wise of me .
This makes you think you 've been right all along .
Hello , Bob .
CHILDREN : I 'm the big boss here .
You 're the little boss .
Good morning . I phoned you at home then I thought I might catch you here .
I didn 't tell you where Bob goes to school .
It wasn 't difficult . We have a minor problem here .
Yes ?
The detective who was in charge of tracing your wife didn 't come home last night .
So ?
He wasn 't at home this morning and he hasn 't reported to the office .
Before we start to get worried ...
When was he going to check it ? Yesterday or today ?
I don 't know .
Please don 't misunderstand me .
That detective could 've gotten drunk and spent the night with whores ,
although that 's not much likely . He could have died of a heart attack
If our detective doesn 't show up by noon I 'll have to notify the police .
The police will start digging into your problem . That 's how it is .
You and I can claim professional secrecy
but you have to give me the address the detective gave you .
Sebastianstrasse 87 , floor 1 .
Have you been to that address yourself or telephoned ?
- No . - Very sensible of you .
But may I ask why not ?
I had the impression that you were tremendously interested
in finding your wife .
Yes , I was .
I suppose I still am .
But that was out of pure , blind ambition .
And you know something ?
I don 't feel like there 's anything much ambitious left in me .
I see .
So I don 't even have to ask you as a personal favour
not to come to the office until I contact you .
Why ?
Precisely because of the ... delicacy of your feelings ,
you might be able to understand that ...
my interest in the case comes from the fact that I ...
live with that detective .
I 'll be calling .
( SOUND OF SCRUBBING )
I have to talk to you .
That 's what I guessed .
Have you ever seen this man ?
Do I have to answer you ?
Well , you have to answer to someone eventually .
That 's too easy .
But it 's you ... or the police , right ?
Right .
Why ?
You 're scaring me .
Am I not scared ?
Oh yes .
I see .
Darkness is easeful .
And the temptation to let go
promises so much comfort after the pain .
He 's in there .
( SQUELCHING AND DRIPPING )
( SQUELCHING AND DEEP BREATHING )
Mein Gott !
He is very tired .
He made love to me all night .
Emmanuel .
He is still unfinished , you know .
Emmanuel !
( SHOUTS )
( ANNA SPEAKING FRENCH )
Un ... deux ... cou-de-pied
chassé , developpé
à la deuxiéme arabesque .
Tighten your stomach .
Et attitude .
Relevé .
Relevé !
Ach ! Knee !
Your foot ... Look at your hand .
Tighter stomach .
Your back , up your leg .
Up your knee .
Look at your hands .
Tighten your stomach .
Your back .
Your foot .
( DANCER GASPING )
- Do it . Hold it . Hold it . - ( SHE WHIMPERS )
Up .
Your knee .
( CRIES OUT )
Hold it . Hold it .
- ( DANCER STILL CRYING OUT ) - Your shoulders down .
Hold it .
Hold . Hold it .
Hold it . Hold it .
Hold it .
( DANCER SCREAMING )
More . More .
That 's very good ! Very , very good .
Very good .
That 's very good . Good girl .
From now on she 'll know how much righteous anger
and sheer will she 's got in her to say ,
" I can do as well . I can be better . I 'm the best . "
Only in this case can she become a success .
Nobody took me there .
That 's why I 'm with you .
Because you say " I " for me .
( PROJECTOR WHIRRS )
( CHAIR CREAKS )
Yes , I 'm thinking about him ,
but I recognise the self who has just done something horrible
like the sister I 've casually met on the street . " Hello , sister . "
It 's like those two sisters of Faith and Chance .
Well , Faith can 't exclude Chance but Chance ...
Oh sh ... !
Well , it 's like those two sisters of Faith and Chance .
My faith can 't exclude chance but my chance can explain faith .
My faith didn 't allow me to wait for chance
and chance didn 't give me enough faith .
Well ...
And then I read that private life is a stage ,
only I 'm playing in many parts that are smaller than me and yet I still play them .
I suffer , I believe , I am ...
But at the same time I know there 's a third possibility , you know ,
like cancer or madness , but cancer and madness contort reality .
The possibility I 'm talking about pierces reality .
Well , I 'm unable to say it , maybe ,
maybe it 's impossible to say , maybe I 'm too stupid .
You 're looking at me as if you ...
You 're looking at me as if to tell me that I need you to fill me up ,
as if I 'm an empty space .
Well , I love you too but what makes me go on is to know he 'll return
and that I 'll make him suffer and I 'll hurt him and I 'm betraying him ,
but ... this brings me small rewards .
Yet I can 't exist by myself because I 'm afraid of myself ,
because I 'm the maker of my own evil .
Because ...
Because I 'm ...
Goodness is only some kind of reflection upon evil .
That 's the way it is .
Ah ! ( SHE SIGHS )
What are you doing ?
I 'm sorting out his things to take to the laundry .
I could do it myself .
But it 's my job .
- I 'm very good at it . - Very kind of you , but ...
Maybe you could do it when Bob is at home .
It 's getting ... so difficult for you , isn 't it ?
You 're not as ...
You 're not as strong or as sure of yourself as you thought you were
so you keep coming back .
You must be ... You must be
torn apart .
I can ... I can think more clearly now .
I guess ...
I guess when you 're there
you want to be home , and when you 're home
you want to be there .
If what you have there is so strong for you .
If it 's what you never had ...
stick to it , keep it .
( SHE CRIES OUT )
It 's very quiet here when you 're out .
It was very quiet when you weren 't here .
Come over here . Let 's just see if we can sit together peacefully still .
( CRIES GETTING LOUDER )
Is it the same there ?
( SCREAMS ) No !
Can you tell me now ?
I messed everything up .
Even Bob .
I 've been a cheat , a liar ,
completely alone , wounded .
And you think I 'm immoral shit .
I think so too but not for the same reasons .
( SCREAMS ) I feel nothing for no-one !
It 's as if the two sisters were too exhausted to fight any more .
You know these women wrestling in an arena of mud
with their hands locked at each other 's throats
each waiting to see who will die first .
And both staring at me .
( SHE WHIMPERS )
( WHIMPER ECHOES )
( WHIMPERING GETS LOUDER )
( SHE CRIES )
( SHE CRIES AGAIN )
( CHURCH BELLS RINGING )
( LAUGHS HYSTERICALLY )
( LAUGHTER BECOMES SCREAMING )
( LOUD PANTING )
( PANTING BECOMES SCREAMING )
( SHE SCREAMS )
What I miscarried there was Sister Faith .
And what was left is Sister Chance .
So I had to take care of my faith
to protect it .
And that 's what you 're doing there ?
Yes .
You look uglier .
You 've hardened .
For the first time , you look
vulgar to me .
You know , I remember when I was a kid .
Have you ever seen a dying dog , you know , one of those old dogs
that comes to die under the ... under the porch of the house ?
At the last moment ,
it ... yelps
in terror
as if it 's seen something real .
I want you to take off the ring and the wristwatch I gave you
last time I came home .
Don 't forget to give him his yoghurt .
No .
I have to go .
If I threw myself at your feet and yelped , would you still walk over me ?
Yes .
Hello , this is Anna 's husband speaking .
HEINRICH 'S MOTHER : Anna 's not here .
I don 't have the slightest idea what 's happening to her .
- Do you love your son ? - Sir !
Tell him that I love him too .
I love everybody and everything . I accept everything . I have become wise
and profound and good .
Do you want to talk to him ? We are just having coffee .
No , I don 't want to talk to him . I ...
I don 't want your coffee to get cold , either , I certainly love your coffee .
Just tell Heinrich that Anna 's address is Sebastianstrasse 87 , first floor .
Five , six , seven , sky !
Eight , seven , six , five , four , three ...
Madam teacher , my apologies for being late .
No , it 's all right .
Anyway , we were waiting for you .
Thank you . And goodbye , Bob .
What is it ?
My name .
( PANTING )
I respected your wish to be alone , I thought you needed the time ,
but now it 's time enough .
Besides , what are you doing here anyway ?
Don 't resist me .
You know I 'm stronger than you .
I 'm the only one in your life who has rights on you
because I don 't claim any .
I brought it from India .
You know , this is what the French poet Michaux was writing about .
I kept it for you .
With this , love opens to absolutely unknown horizons .
Absolutely unknown .
Anna .
We are made to swim in the centre of the stream .
Not to wait on the dry banks .
Yes .
Exactly .
I showed you the door to God
and this door is always open .
Come .
( DRIPPING )
This is a joke .
( HEAVY BREATHING )
What is it ?
Anna !
These must be removed . They are beginning to smell .
This can 't be true .
I 've got to keep this place clean and well .
Oh my God !
Are you going to help me ?
Heinrich .
You are no different from anyone else .
We are all the same
but in different words .
With different bodies ,
different versions ,
like insects .
Meat !
( HE GASPS )
Anna !
( PHONE RINGS )
( IMITATES ENGINE )
( IMITATES AEROPLANE )
Calling all ambulances and fire engines to the scene of the crash .
And two trucks .
( BOB IMITATES SIREN )
Where ?
( DOORBELL BUZZES )
Can you answer the door , Bob ?
Now , listen , Heinrich . Just stay where you are .
I paid a fortune for the cab .
At the bar at the corner .
Bleed for a while .
I 'll be there as soon as I can .
My son took the car , an automatic one .
- Can you look after Bob till I get back ? - What is it ?
It 's Mummy calling me .
( FLY BUZZING )
( NERVOUS LAUGHTER )
( GASPING )
( HE SCREAMS )
( HISSING )
( FLY BUZZING )
( MARK HUMMING )
( ARCADE MACHINE PLAYS TUNE )
No , not out here .
Go to the toilet .
Need a Tampax ?
How can you joke while I 'm so hurt .
There are corpses in there , at least two bodies .
I thought she was pulling my leg , but no , there 's blood .
She cuts them .
A monster , a joke , but it was alive .
You 're drunk , Heinrich .
She cuts us to pieces , Mark .
Maybe she just didn 't want to see you .
Don 't joke . I 'm not joking .
Oh yes , you 're not joking , so what do you want ?
Don 't you understand ? She 's killing people .
I understand she 's killing people , so why do you call me and not the police ?
She is sick , Mark , doesn 't that mean anything to you ?
There are dead bodies there !
I don 't believe you .
Maybe you 're stoned on some shit you suck on .
Some mushroom you gobble ?
Perhaps you did it to yourself .
Maybe you 're learning how to suffer . Now , that would be an achievement .
- I feel for people . - You talk for people .
- You take their wives . - ( SHOUTS ) I take what I want !
And I 'm at peace with myself .
Nobody saw me come in . Nobody .
I called you because we have to do something to help her .
Why ?
It isn 't normal . It wasn 't even human . It was ...
Divine ?
Perhaps you met God a moment ago and you didn 't even realise it .
Now , you believe in God , don 't you ? Certainly .
In that great incomprehensible God whom you reached through fucking , or dope .
Am I right ?
Look , Mark , that woman is crazy . We have to do something .
We ?
I 'm not going to do anything .
I can 't leave it this way . It 's Anna . It 's murder .
You 're not a man , Mark . You 're a woman .
All right , if you don 't intend to do anything and want to keep me silent ,
you will have to pay . You have money , I know it .
You have to get me out of here , and send me on a long trip to restore my harmony !
I deserve it ! If you had only seen what I saw !
( HE RETCHES )
Heinrich , help me out of here , I 'm sick !
I 'm the one who is wounded - not you .
Please !
( TOILET FLUSHES )
- ( COUGHING ) - ( GAS HISSING )
( WOMAN LAUGHS )
God 's light avenge them ,
giving it out clean and getting it back dirty .
( SHE GURGLES )
( WHISPERS ) Do you believe in God ?
( SOBS ) In God ?
It 's in me .
Take me .
- Did Margie see it ? - Yes .
- That 's why you killed her . - She tried to take it away from me .
- Is this faith that helpless ? - It needs to be protected .
- Like a child . - Yes .
You know , for me , God is still under the porch , where the dog died .
And on the branch of the eucalyptus tree , where I 'd lie for hours ,
and watch how the clouds change the colour of the grass below .
I need money .
I had to leave there .
Oh , I 've cleaned all the mess . I washed the floor , I made the bed .
I didn 't know where to go .
It became so unsafe there .
People can 't stop trying to take it away from me .
OK .
Now leave me the car .
Take Margie 's keys and go to her place and wait there .
Can you drive a motorbike ?
Heinrich taught me .
It 's outside .
Now , I 'll take care of Bob and everything .
I 'll go to the bank on Monday and take the money out .
If Bob wakes up , tell him ...
I will .
It 's only me . Go to sleep .
I have to go .
Please close the door .
- Because it 's here with you ? - Yes .
( DOGS BARKING )
( PHONE RINGS )
- I 'm sorry to disturb you , but ... - Yes ?
You understand that it is very late , and Heinrich hasn 't called me yet .
He calls me every night so I won 't worry about when he comes home .
Maybe ... Maybe he just forgot your number .
No , you don 't understand . Mothers always feel it when their sons are in trouble .
Are you worried ... ?
Are you worried that he 's not there having sex with my wife ?
They should come here .
I 've put clean sheets on the bed and they could have dinner .
Are you quite sure you know who you are talking to ?
I am .
- I went there . - Where ?
I was worried , you understand .
There isn 't any apartment there under the address you gave me .
There 's only a smoking hole that the police won 't allow anybody to come near .
So I went to a bar at the corner to call home , to find out ...
if Heimlich had returned .
Yes ?
And Heinrich was there .
Nobody could identify him .
Yes ?
I recognised his body , of course .
Did you identify him for the police ?
No , it was only Heinrich 's body . But his soul was not there .
Perhaps he and his soul had parted company before .
You don 't know what you 're talking about .
No , you 're quite right . I don 't have any idea what I 'm talking about .
He must have seemed to you better and more beautiful than you .
When Anna met him , she immediately worshipped his soul .
And you sent him there .
Now , listen to me .
I recognise Heinrich 's superiority in every way .
I was proud that Anna accepted him .
Now Anna has gone missing
and I 'm here ,
all alone , you understand , with our little son .
Now , I must find her - maybe it 's her fault .
I 'll find her , and I 'll force her to tell me what she 's done with Heinrich 's soul .
And then I 'll come to you and tell you .
Won 't you come up ?
I 'm in a rush .
Is it your wife ?
Here .
Will you promise me something ?
Yes .
Whatever it is .
I promise .
( MOANING )
( MOANING GETS LOUDER )
( SHE CRIES OUT )
Almost .
- Almost . - Yes .
Heinrich 's dead .
Isn 't he ?
Yes .
Have you found Anna ?
You come like the angel of death .
The one who kills .
I have thought about killing her .
And now ?
Now I don 't know .
Did you see anything that made you change your mind ?
I don 't know what I saw but Heinrich saw it too .
And you came to tell me that you don 't know where Heinrich 's soul is .
Yes .
I can see it in your face .
It would be good to think that the soul lives separately from the body .
That the soul lives for ever and the body only for a time .
But it isn 't so .
I don 't know any more .
I do .
I have to be ... on my son 's side .
Even if he has made you unhappy .
I know all there is to know about him .
That I love him .
Yes .
I was wondering which is worse .
Take away someone 's wife ,
hurt a child
or to kill .
He also had a wife and a child .
I used to like her .
I liked your Anna too .
I had to like both of them
since they loved him .
The world is only what it is .
Murderous .
If we are the best of it .
You don 't have to worry about me .
I don 't want to be here
if Heinrich is not around any more .
( WINDOW CREAKS )
That dog didn 't die of old age .
What about you , Mark ?
Our man won 't confide or deal with your successor , he wants you .
In fact , Mark , there is no successor .
We can take care of drowning dogs ,
but please help us take care of the drowning world .
Don 't you think it 's uneconomical to waste yourself on dogs ?
Even dogs you love ?
I met a man who loved everything .
And he died in a flood of shit .
We know . That 's just details .
When I was a boy ...
I had a dog and his name was Louis .
When he crawled under the porch to die , I stayed there with him .
So what ?
I wanted to see what it was that made him crawl under there .
Nobody 's a boy any more .
Must we prove it ?
This is the address .
Back up , then full speed , and crash into the police car .
My pleasure , sir .
Out of the car !
( HE YELLS )
( GASPING )
( CHURCH BELLS RINGING )
( CAR ENGINE )
- ( DOOR SLAMS ) - ( FOOTSTEPS )
Anna ?
Run away ! Go ! Go !
How could you find me ?
How could I not ?
I wanted to show it to you .
It is finished now .
Oh yes .
So hard to live with it . Eh , brother ?
Is there a way out ?
Will you help me ?
Yes .
Take it .
Shoot them .
( VOICES FROM BELOW )
How do you want to finish it ?
( DOORBELL RINGS )
Would you open it please ?
Why not , Bob ?
It could be your father .
Don 't open .
Well , I want to .
- But I want to . - Don 't open .
Don 't open .
( SHOUTS ) Don 't open .
Please don 't open .
Don 't open it .
Don 't open .
Don 't open . Don 't open .
Don 't open . Don 't open . Don 't open .
Don 't open .
Don 't open . Don 't open .
( SIREN WAILS )
( LOUD EXPLOSIONS )